# Kostas **Pagratis**

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2061 Sicily Cir. Longmont CO, 80503

【 (303) 817-1605 | ■ kostas@pagratis.us | ★ https://kpagratis.github.io/resume

#### Summary\_

Highly motivated and experienced software engineer with experience in management and deployment of Software Engineering projects including requirements definition, solutions design, implementation, maintenance, testing, support, deployment, enhancements, and final delivery. Knowledgeable in managing multi-functional development teams while utilizing Agile methodologies. Innate ability to adapt to new technologies, architectures, and solutions while striving to ensure code quality and Engineering best practices.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Twitter Boulder, CC

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Oct. 2015 - Present

- Developed an embedded MySQL testing framework now included in finagle and finatra OSS project on github facilitating embedded integration testing for MySQL solutions.
- Developed internal enhancements of MySQL testing framework to seamlessly integrate with build and CI systems used at Twitter.
- · Drove widespread adoption of MySQL testing framework by migrating users from a deprecated solution.
- Delivered widespread code health improvements across all of Twitter's code including upgrading mockito across thousands of tests.
- Mentored junior developers and interns from new hire to first promotions.
- Full stack development of Twitters developer platform encompassing all levels of the technology stack from backed service development to front end React/Redux front end.
- · Developed a bulk compliance solution to help Twitter data customers keep large datasets in compliance.

Flatirons Solutions Boulder, CO

TECHNICAL LEAD May 2008 - Oct. 2015

- Led various teams tackling custom digital asset management projects across multiple sectors.
- Implemented global portal for Disney Consumer Products customers to acquire digital assets while improving processing times by multiple orders of magnitude.
- Implemented a test authoring and compliation system for Cambridge Assessments and supported the project through the entire lifecycle starting at in depth data-modeling and discovery through final delivery and support.
- · Modernized Boeing's technical writing apparatus with a new bespoke solution built upon partner technologies.

Rogue Wave Software Boulder, CC

CONSULTING ENGINEER II

Aug. 2005 - May 2008

- · Provided on site consulting with customers for requirements gathering, design specification, solution installation, testing, and debugging.
- Ported RogueWave products between various operating systems and compilers including but not limited to RedHat, Solaris, HP-UX, and IRIX, gcc, SunPro, HPaCC, and XLC.
- Established expertise and comfort with exploring and debugging unfamiliar code-bases.

### **Education**

#### University of Colorado

Boulder Colorado

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

# **Skills**

**Recent** Scala, Java, JavaScript, Python, Git, REST, SQL

Past Rust, AWS, GCP, Kafka, Unix Scripting, Ant, Maven, C, C++, React, Redux, AngularJS

NOVEMBER 8, 2022 KOSTAS PAGRATIS